我们讨论的最后一节是卷，好吗 ?
The last section that we talked
about was volumes, okay?
但愿这对你有帮助而且我们今天要到
And hopefully that was helpful for
you, and we're gonna get in today for
在开发环境中使用容器。
using containers in your
development environments.
我认为这其实是开发人员最迫切的原因之一
And I think this is actually one of
the most compelling reasons for developer
大量的人去学习容器这就是为什么我把这个放在这里的原因
populous at large to learn containers, and
that's actually why I put this in here.
所以我们要经历两种不同的场景。
So we're gonna go through
two different scenarios.
我要给你们展示的第一款是如何使用
The first one I'm gonna show you how
to use dev containers outside of
Visual Studio 代码
Visual Studio Code,
就因为我知道你们都不使用数码演播室密码
just because I know all of you
don't use digital studio code yet.
我来给你的
[LAUGH] I'm coming for you.
我来教你怎么做
So I'll show you how to do that first.
之后我会教你如何使用 Visual Studio 代码
And then after that, I'll show you how
to do it with Visual Studio Code and
" VS " 实际上能让这件事变得很简单
how VS Code will actually
make that really easy.
然后呢最后
And then, lastly,
我们要在进入多个集装箱项目之前先进行联网
we're gonna go over networking before
getting into multi container projects.
好，继续，让我们为您的开发环境使用容器。
All right, so go ahead and let's go into
Using Containers for your Dev Environment.
这就是我们现在要做的
That's what we're gonna go into now.
所以我们对这个想法进行了探讨
So we've kind of explored this idea
of it's really difficult when you
从一个新公司开始，很难起来，
start at a new company,
that it's difficult to get up and
在一家新公司里跑得很快对吧
running quickly at a new company, right?
这就是 dev 容器非常有用的地方，对吧 ?
And so that's where dev containers
can be very useful, right?
如果他们能给你个 Docker 文件然后说
It'd be useful if they could just
hand you a Docker file and say, hey,
这就是我们的开发环境
here's what our developer environment is.
如果你在这里点击就可以了
If you just click start here,
then everything just spins up and
马上开始工作对吧
starts working right away, right?
这很有说服力，对吧 ?
That's pretty compelling, right?
我记得在我在 Reddit 工作之前工作的初创公司
I remember at one of the startups I
worked at before I worked at Reddit,
我必须启动一个开发者环境。
I had to start up a developer environment.
这可能让我更有两个或几个
And it probably took me
the better part of two or
只要花三个星期就能找到工作
three weeks just to get
everything working right.
我将在特定版本的 JVM 中，然后它必须是特定版本
I'd be in a specific version of the JVM,
and then it had to be a specific version
就能得到那版本的角化工作了
of npm to get that version
of Angular working.
它是人类痛苦的鲁贝 - 戈德堡机器，让我们这样说吧。
It was a Rube Goldberg machine of human
suffering, let's put it that way.
因此，我认为容器在您的环境中可以真正为您解决。
So that's what I think containers in your
dev environment can really solve for you.
显然，我是一个 JavaScript 工程师。
So, obviously, I'm a JavaScript engineer.
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything about Go,
但我们要用围棋来证明这一点
but we're gonna be using Go here for
a little bit just to prove the point
你不需要了解这些事情是如何运作的
you don't have to understand the inner
machinations of how these things work.
能为你工作好吗
It can just work for you, okay?
所以我想你们很多人可能听说过雨果
So I imagine many of you
have probably heard of Hugo.
它是一个非常非常受欢迎的静态站点生成器，可与 Gatsby 或
It's a very, very popular static site
generator, comparable to Gatsby or
杰基尔什么的
Jekyll or something like that.
很棒很多人都用它
It's great, lots of people use it.
我觉得 Fronend Masters 在他们的网站上使用它对吧
I think Frontend Masters uses
it on their website, right?
也许吧
Maybe?
>> 是。
&gt;&gt; Yes.
>> 酷，看?
&gt;&gt; Cool, see?
最近，你已经用了雨果网站，或者现在。
So you've already used a Hugo website
recently, or maybe currently.
可能是现在
[LAUGH] Probably currently,
很酷吧
that's cool, right?
但我不知道该怎么做
But I don't know how to set it up.
我从来没有为自己设定过，因为我不是围棋的开发者。
I've never had to set it up for
myself, because I'm not a Go developer.
我没必要和它乱搞
I haven't necessarily
messed around with it.
但我要给你展示我们能做的容器
But I'm gonna show you just using
containers that we can do all this
就像我们自己
kind of ourselves.
所以说你要加入这个新队伍是雨果队
So let's say that you're joining
this new team, it's a Hugo team,
你的新项目就在这里
and your new project is here.
我在这里有一个链接，它将链接到 GitHub 存储库， GitHub 存储在我的 GitHub上。
So I have a link here and it's gonna link
to a GitHub repo, which is on my GitHub.
我们要一起设立这个项目
And we're gonna set up
this project together,
尽管你很多人都不知道怎么用雨果
despite the fact that many of you, I
imagine, don't know how to use Hugo, okay?
所以我们要用这个容器叫做 " hum-builder " 。
So we're gonna use this container
here called hugo-builder.
我不认识这个人但他们创造了这个容器
And I don't know this person necessarily,
but they created this container,
就在这里，让我们可以在一个容器里运行雨果。
hugo-builder right here, that allows
us to run Hugo inside of a container.
我们将以聪明的方式使用绑定安装
And we're gonna use bind mounts in
a clever way to be able to build
我们的计划
our project.
好的，所以你可能不会看到这个，但是很明显我有些去
Okay, so here, you probably won't see
this, but apparently I have some Go
我无法解决的漏洞不是真正的项目
vulnerabilities I'm not gonna fix,
cuz it's not a real project.
好的，这就是这个项目。
[LAUGH] Okay, and so here's the project.
我们现在要做的就是在这里运行格德克隆
And what we're gonna do now is we're
gonna run git clone right here.
这样你就可以把它复制了
So you can go ahead and copy that.
我就在我的 " 对容器 " 项目中。
And I'm here in my
intro-to-containers project.
如果你看这里我还有其他的项目
If you look here,
I have all the other projects in here, and
我只会说 git 克隆 github btholt/hu-example。
I'm just gonna say git clone
github btholt/hugo-example.
好吧我去举个例子
Okay, I'm gonna go into hugo-example.
我们会说医生
And we're gonna say docker
运行 -rm -it --mount。
run --rm -it --mount.
要使用绑定安装，我将使用 type=bind ，source="$(pwd)" ( 如此) ，
To use our bind mounts, I'm gonna say
type=bind,source="$(pwd)" like this,
这样我们就能拿到目前的工作目录了
so that we can get the current
working directory.
我要说目标 = /src
I'm gonna say target=/src.
然后我们说 -p 13
And then we're gonna say -p 13
13:1313 .
13:1313 cuz that's the port that
它会听我说的
it's gonna be listening on, -u hugo,
然后你就得把名字放在这里
and then you have to put the name here.
那么， jguyo，就像这样。
So, jguyo, like that.
/hugo-builder 。
/hugo-builder.
同样，您也可以完全将此权限从注释中复制。
Again, you can totally just copy
this right off of the notes as well.
然后我们把它钉在一个特定的版本上
And then we're gonna pin
it to a specific version,
只是为了确保它能正常工作所以 0.55
just to make sure this keeps working,
so 0.55.
所以我们到目前为止都做了一切
So we've done everything so far.
这会把我们放到集装箱里
This is gonna drop us into the container,
and
现在我们可以给它一个指挥
now we can give it a command for
us to run.
所以我想让它运行的命令是 hugo 服务器，
So the command that I want
it to run is hugo server,
就像开发环境对吧
which is gonna be like
the development environment, right?
hugo 服务器 -w --bind=0.0.0.0。
hugo server -w --bind=0.0.0.0.
所以，绑定部分是在外部提供，而不仅仅是内部的。
So the bind part is so that it's available
externally, not just internally,
就是这个容器
it's the container.
现在，但愿我们能这样做。
So now, hopefully, if we run this.
我的会说找不到这个的所以它会把这些都拉出来
Mine's gonna say can't find this, so it's
gonna go out there and pull some of these.
看来大概有 20 兆字节的东西给我
It looks like it's gonna be maybe
20 megabytes worth of stuff for me.
这里已经存在了
And this already exists here.
这可能是 Ubuntu 或者
This is probably something like Ubuntu or
我已经在电脑上的阿尔卑斯了对吧
Alpine that I already had on my computer,
right?
这是你的
And here you go.
现在它正在运行，它在本地主机 1313上运行。
Now it's running, and
it's running on local host 1313.
这里是雨果网站，有一个主题，我甚至不知道它是什么主题。
So here is a Hugo website with some random
theme, I don't even know what theme it is.
[ LAUGH] 工作，对吧 ?
[LAUGH] Working, right?
我们把这一切都和雨果一起去了
We got this all up and
running with a Go project with Hugo and
所有这些事情都是无知不知道的
all that kind of stuff running,
with no knowledge of it.
就像在内部工作的黑盒子一样
Like totally black box of
how it's working internally.
如果你是 CSS 开发者或设计师之类的
And if you're a CSS developer or
designer or something like that,
你就可以去和社联乱搞了，你就不用真的知道了，
you can just go in and mess with the CSS
and you don't have to really know and
了解雨果在兜帽下工作的情况
understand how Hugo's
working under the hood.
你可以让另一个处理它的人
You can let the other team
that handles that part of it,
就在这里说 Docker 文件
just say here's the Docker file.
只要你在 Docker 文件里就行了吧
As long as you're in the Docker file,
everything just works, right?
所以我认为这对于团队和个人项目是很有吸引力的，对吧 ?
So I think this is compelling for teams
and for your personal projects, right?
比如说你有一些要用你的项目导出的贝斯波克环境
Like say you have some Bespoke environment
that you need to export with your project
让它工作
for it to work.
你可以把所有东西都设置好然后有人进来
You can just set all that stuff up,
and then someone can come in and
他们就把容器和一切都做了
they just run the container and
everything works.
是吗 ?
Yeah?
> > 这就是我们在Fron趋向大师赛上做的
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's literally what
we do at Frontend Masters.
这就是它的运作方式。
This is how it works.
> > 嗯，我们有雨果和 Go，所有东西都在一个容器里。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, we have Hugo and Go,
and everything is in a container.
所以你就做容器，开始工作。
And so you just build the container and
start working.
>> 这就被正式称为 " Fron倾向大师 " 建筑。
&gt;&gt; There you go, this is now officially
dubbed the Frontend Masters architecture.
我觉得太棒了
[LAUGH] I think it's great.
雨果就是一个很简单的例子
And Hugo is a pretty
simple example of this.
我想这里大多数人都可以自己建立雨果
I imagine most people here
could set up Hugo on their own.
是我做的对吗
I did make that project, right?
所以我没那么久
So it didn't take me that long.
但我相信你能想象到
But I'm sure you could
imagine some very difficult,
也许像 JVM 一样难以设置
maybe like JVM sort of thing
that's difficult to set up.
所有这些东西都可以组合成一个容器或者多个容器
And all of those things could be combined
into a container, or multiple containers,
而且很容易就能分享
and makes it very easy to share.
你有问题吗
Do you have a question?
>> 因此，如果我向某人发送 Docker 版本，那么
&gt;&gt; So with that approach,
if I send somebody the Docker version so
它们可以在本地运行，这也减轻了安装软件包的需求吗 ?
they can run locally, is this also
mitigating the need to install package?
比如当你有了一个像我们刚刚复制的爬虫类似的
Like when you get a pull down repo
like we just cloned this one,
通常执行 Yarn 或 npm 安装。
usually do a Yarn or npm install.
我们是否绕过这条路，只处理货柜的路线 ?
Do we bypass that,
just deal with the container route?
>> 所以我要给你们演示如何在这里用 VS .
&gt;&gt; So I'm gonna show you how to do this
with VS Code here in just a second, and
它会让我们更进一步
it'll take that even a step further.
一般来说，有新的依赖关系是好的，对，
In general, it's good to have
fresh dependencies, right,
因为事情不断更新
because things are constantly updating.
就好像是我不知道我不知道
And it's like, maybe it's like,
I don't know, let's say,
Lodash 发布一个版本，它将中断，它是补丁版本。
Lodash releases a version that breaks and
it's a patch version.
你想抓住那个发展的东西对吧
You wanna catch that in development,
right?
我想你需要在那里做交易
There's trade offs there that
you need to make, I guess.
所以它可以，对，你可以把一切都烤到其中。
So it can, right,
you can totally bake everything into it.
但这一切都很酷又回到你的位置
But what's cool about this, and
coming kinda back to your point,
如果我回来看看我的 " 去 " 项目，举个例子
if I come back in here and I look at
my Go project here, hugo-example.
所以如果我来这里
So if I come here.
我想我不记得你是怎么做到的
I think, anyway,
I can't remember how you do this.
但最棒的是，我不是真正的编辑，对吧 ?
But what's great about this is,
I'm not actually live editing, right?
因为它是使用与我的主机共享的绑定安装，对吗 ?
Because it's using a bind mount
that's shared with my host, right?
所以如果我开始打字
So if I start typing things,
也会改变容器里的东西对吧
it's gonna be modifying the things that
are in the container as well, right?
它可以，它可以减轻它，但是
So it can, it can mitigate that, but
你只需要做你想做的决定
you just have to make your decisions
of how you want that to work.
所以，我们要回到依赖关系的地方。
So actually coming back to
the point of dependencies here.
如果我在本地计算机上执行 npm 安装，然后将安装绑定到
If I do an npm install on my local
computer and then I bind mount that into
Ubuntu to be run， we native dependencies of native dependencies， right?
Ubuntu to to be run, we still have that
issue of native dependencies, right?
所以如果我为麦克建造 Node - sass ，然后我在 Ubuntu 中运行它，
So if I build Node-sass for Mac and
then I try and run it in Ubuntu,
它不会工作的对吧卡兹是建在麦肯的
it's not gonna work, right,
cuz it was built for Mac.
所以我们有这样的一个问题，就是要装进集装箱，
So we have this kind of issue that we have
to bind mount into the container, and
然后运行 npm 安装。
then afterwards run npm install.
因为需要在容器中安装 npm 。
Because it needs to be npm
installed within the container.
所以你可以把它们烧了，这就是你所建议的。
So you can burn them in,
which is what you suggested.
您只需导出已在其中构建的依赖关系的容器。
And you just export the container with
the dependencies already hard built in.
但那种烂透了因为如果我晚上跑了
But that kind of sucks a little
bit because if I run npm,
就好像我在后面安装另一个附属关系
it's like if I install another
dependency afterwards,
经常是 Node 开发者在做的事，我们又有同样的问题。
which is frequently what Node developers
are doing, we have the same problem again.
所以有几种方法可以做到。
So there's a couple ways you can do it.
如果你这样做，没有 Visual Studio 代码，我通常是这样做的
If you're doing it this way without Visual
Studio Code, the way that I usually do it
我只是连接到正在运行的容器，而我第一次运行 npm 安装。
is I just attach to the running container,
and I run npm install for the first time.
之后就会好了对吧
And then after that,
it's usually okay, right?
每次重新启动容器时，都必须执行此操作。
You just kinda have to do that every
time that you restart up the container.
这很烦人但很有用
It's annoying, but it works.
进入 Visual Studio 代码很聪明地说我是
And moving into Visual Studio Code,
which it's just smart enough to say, I'm
你一定要做个 npm 的安装，而且它就是给你做的。
pretty sure you're gonna need to do an npm
install and it just does it for you, so.
但我们会去的只有一会儿
But we'll get there, just a second.